

Address Dhore Farm, New Sangavi, Pune-411027

Contact +91 7767984499 mandalenikita08@gmail.com

**Date of Birth** 18.03.1989

## **PROFILE**

Strategic and result driven Business Analyst with total 10+ years of rich & broad-based experience in project planning, executing and implementing projects, managing project resources, and taking ownership on timely delivery of products in every sprint. Extensive experience in various industry sectors like IT Services, BFSI, Healthcare, Telecom etc. Ability to handle multiple projects. Equipped with excellent communication skills, work ethics and possesses a strong sense of leadership with a commendable record of accomplishment.

## **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- ✓ Good communication written and oral skills
- ✓ Excellent conceptual and analytical skills
- ✓ Root cause Analysis
- ✓ Requirement Gathering & Analysis
- ✓ Project costing/Budgeting
- ✓ Agile & Waterfall Methodologies
- ✓ Risk Analysis & Decision making
- ✓ Planning & Project management
- ✓ Documentation

## **AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Top Performer Recognition Award
- Employee of the year
- Employee of the Quarter & Month
- Platinum Member

#### **SOFTWARE SKILLS**

Power BI



# NIKITA MANDALE

Sr. Business Analyst

#### Linkedin

linkedin.com/in/nikitamandale

## **EDUCATION**

06.2006 - 05.2009

University of Pune

Bachelor of Computer Science (BCS)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

12.2022 - present

# Drizzle IT Services

Senior. Business Analyst

- 4 years of Business Analysis experience with in-depth knowledge of business processes in BFSI industry.
- In-depth knowledge of SDLC methodologies. Vast experience working in Agile Scrum.
- Well versed with leading industry tools like Jira, MS Visio, MS Word, MS Powerpoint to develop various project deliverables.
- Work closely with businesses/Consultants, understands their needs, gather requirements, analysis, create user stories, UML diagrams and forward it to the development team.
- Documenting Functional & Non-Functional requirements/user stories for data integration & synchronization.
- Experienced in SQL queries. Worked in Oracle & PGAdmin tool to fetch data through sql queries.
- Create PBI(Product Backlog items) & identifies the priority line items from the backlog in time.
- Identifies any potential risks, impacts, and/or gaps in the scope and/or requirements of the project scope & suggests alternative solutions to mitigate them.
- Skilled at reviewing test cases making sure they are in accordance with requirements, assist in overall testing process and conducting UAT along with Test Managers.

09.2022 - 11.2022

#### CodeElan Technologies

Senior. Business Analyst

- Experience handling BFSI project. Have in-depth knowledge of Software development life cycle(SDLC) methodologies, assisting and working as Business analyst on several projects.
- Defines project scope, goals and deliverables that support business goals in collaboration with project team and stakeholders.
- Defining user stories & specifications for new API & file based data migration & integration solutions. Document functional & non-functional requirements/user stories for data integration.
- Support in UAT, Go-live.



### **CERTIFICATIONS**

 Certified IT Business Analyst (IIBA Certification- 2023) Institute: COEPD

Digital Marketing (Oct- 2022)
 Institute: SEO Engineers

## LANGUAGES

English  $\bigstar \bigstar \bigstar \bigstar \bigstar \bigstar$ Hindi  $\bigstar \bigstar \bigstar \bigstar \bigstar \bigstar \bigstar$ 

# **PERSONALITY**

- ✓ Communicative
- ✓ Punctuality
- ✓ Organized
- ✓ Planner

## **HOBBY**







Travelling & Exploring new places 09.2018 - 07.2022

#### Clindox India Pvt Ltd

Senior. Business Analyst

- Have in-depth knowledge of SDLC methodologies, Agile,
   Scrum and Waterfall methodologies.
- Supported major Healthcare, Clinical research projects by assessing client business needs & applying IT solutions(EDC), Randomization.
- Engage client to gather software requirements & ensure alignment with development team.
- Worked on Agile methodology in the entire SDLC.
   Participation in daily & weekly calls with the team and Stakeholders.
- Identifies any potential risks, impacts, and gaps in the project scope & suggests solutions.
- Managing Change requests and participate in Change Control Board (CCB) approval process and facilitating deployments.
- Develop high level project plans for implementation of projects.
- Perform SIT, UAT.
- Excellent Communication skills & adept at facilitating walkthrough and training sessions.

#### 05.2015 - 10.2017

#### Demandshore Pvt Ltd

Business Analyst/Pre-Sales Business Analyst

- Worked with business users to identify and analyse the key business requirements in BFSI, Telecom, IT Services industry.
- Analyze business requirements & processes through document analysis, JAD sessions, interviews, questionnaire & workflow analysis.
- Create RFP & RFQ.
- Develop detailed BRD, FRD as per client requirements. Communicate with development team & Stakeholders.
- Participate in complete SDLC process using Agile, Scrum methodologies.
- Participated in Change control meetings recommending appropriate action after analysis of changing requirements.
- Perform SIT & UAT with internal team & respective stakeholders and update them with the progress of the project.
- Worked extensively with MS Office suite for preparing status report.

#### 07.2012 - 04.2015

#### IBM

Sr. Technical Support Executive/Practitioner

- International Broadband & Telecom support experience.
   Responsible for handling client queries, tickets and liaising with Stakeholder in order to address and resolve reported issues in a timely manner.
- Identify, troubleshoot technical hardware & software issues & escalate priority issues as per client specifications by taking remote connection.

